A Guide to the Jacqueline Upham Oliver Collection, 1869-2004
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Jacqueline Upham Oliver Collection, 1869-2004
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-52
0.5 linear feet
The Jacqueline Upham Oliver Collection consists of 0.5 linear feet and spans the years 1869-2004 and contains school certificates, photographs, correspondence, alumni directories, a pin, newspapers, books, photocopies, notes, and birth, death, and marriage certificates.
Oliver, Jacqueline Delores Upham (1935-2009)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Historical and Biographical Information
Jacqueline Delores Upham was born on November 2, 1935 in Aitkin, Minnesota to Jack and Lorena Upham. She attended Boone Elementary School in Watauga, North Carolina. In 1946, the family moved to Annandale, Virginia where she attended Annandale Elementary School and later graduated from Fairfax High School in 1953. In November 1956, Upham joined the U.S. Marines Corps. After graduating from boot camp in Parris Island, the Marines stationed her at MCB Quantico working as a clerk. She left the Corps as a Private First Class on May 2, 1958, married Bernard “Doug” Oliver, and returned to Virginia in 1960.
She had a 27-year career with the Fairfax County Water Authority first as a clerk-typist and working her way up to an Engineer Technician before retiring in 1988. On May 15, 1976, after 18 years of civilian life, she joined the U.S. Naval Reserves as a DK2. She was recalled to Desert Storm in February 1991 and stationed at Cherry Point for 119 days. Oliver retired in November 1995 at age 60 and spent her retirement traveling, working on genealogical research, and volunteering at the Women in Military Service for America Memorial in Arlington Cemetery. She died on July 3, 2009 in Arlington, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The Jacqueline Upham Oliver Collection consists of 0.5 linear feet and spans the years 1869-2004 and contains school certificates, photographs, correspondence, alumni directories, a pin, newspapers, books, photocopies, notes, and birth, death, and marriage certificates. Subjects include Fairfax High School class reunions and genealogical research of the Upham, Oliver, and Lillard families. Original marriage certificates for Jack Yates Upham and Lorena Mae Lillard (1932); Glenn Wakley Upham and Gertude C. Yates (1906); and Andrew Jackson Upham and Isadora Adell Wakeley (1869) are also included. School certificates are from Annandale Elementary School in Annandale, Virginia and Boone Elementary School in Watauga, North Carolina.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
1961 “The Buccaneer” East Carolina College yearbook discarded due to mold damage.
Index Terms
Annandale (Va.); Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.); Lillard Family; Oliver Family; Oliver, Jacqueline Delores Upham (1935-2009); Upham Family
Container List
- Certificates and Photographs, Annandale E.S. (Annandale, Va.) and Boone E.S. (Watauga, N.C.), 1944-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.) 20th Class Reunion of the Class of 1953, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.) 25th Class Reunion of the Class of 1953, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.) 30th Class Reunion of the Class of 1953, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.) 35th Class Reunion of the Class of 1953, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.) 40th Class Reunion of the Class of 1953, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fairfax High School (Fairfax, Va.) 45th Class Reunion of the Class of 1953, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newspaper. Annandale News (Annandale, Va.) Vol. 1 No. 24, (Jackie Upham mentioned), 1953 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Upham, Jacqueline. Military Service, 1957-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Upham, Jack Y., 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Upham, James B. Origins of the Pledge of Allegiance, 1938-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Oliver and Upham Family Pedigree Charts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Birth, death, and marriage certificates, 1869-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Book, “The Amazing Story of the Uphams in America” by Sharon Taylor, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Yearbook pages. 1961 “The Buccaneer” East Carolina University, J.D. Upham Freshman class, 1961 (Photocopies), Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Our Puritan Ancestors by Marian Cook Perlot, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Upham, Jarem [Civil War Ancestor], 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)